<doc>
	<doi>10.1145/3397271.3401198</doi>
	<title>Bundle Recommendation with Graph Convolutional Networks</title>
	<abstract>Bundle recommendation aims to recommend a bundle of items for a user to consume as a whole. Existing solutions integrate user-item interaction modeling into bundle recommendation by sharing model parameters or learning in a multi-task manner, which cannot explicitly model the affiliation between items and bundles, and fail to explore the decision-making when a user chooses bundles. In this work, we propose a graph neural network model named BGCN (short forBundle Graph Convolutional Network ) for bundle recommendation. BGCN unifies user-item interaction, user-bundle interaction and bundle-item affiliation into a heterogeneous graph. With item nodes as the bridge, graph convolutional propagation between user and bundle nodes makes the learned representations capture the item level semantics. Through training based on hard-negative sampler, the user's fine-grained preferences for similar bundles are further distinguished. Empirical results on two real-world datasets demonstrate the strong performance gains of BGCN, which outperforms the state-of-the-art baselines by 10.77% to 23.18%.</abstract>
	<contexts>
		<context id="01" section="introduction">
			<s cites="2,6,7">Most existing works for bundle recommendation [2, 6, 7] regard item and bundle recommendation as two separate tasks, and associate them by sharing model parameters.</s>
			<s cites="3">A recent study [3] proposed a multi-task framework that transfers the benefits of the item recommendation task to the bundle recommendation to alleviate the scarcity of user-bundle interactions.</s>
			<s>Despite effectiveness, we argue that they suffer from three major limitations:</s>
		</context>
		<context id="02" section="related work">
			<s>Although bundles are currently widely used everywhere, few efforts have been made in solving the bundle recommendation problem.</s>
			<s cites="6,2">List Recommendation Model (LIRE) [6] and Embedding Factorization Machine (EFM) [2] simultaneously utilized the users' interactions with both items and bundles under the BPR framework.</s>
			<s cites="7">The Bundle BPR (BBPR) Model [7] made use of the parameter previously learned through an item BPR model.</s>
			<s cites="3">Recently, Deep Attentive Multi-Task Model (DAM) [3] jointly modeled user-bundle interactions and user-item interactions in a multi-task manner.</s>
		</context>
		<context id="03" section="related work">
			<s cites="5">The basic idea of graph convolutional networks (GCN) [5] is to reduce the high-dimensional adjacency information of a node in the graph to a low-dimensional vector representation.</s>
			<s>With the strong power of learning structure, GCN is widely applied in recommender systems.</s>
			<s cites="1" anonymised="true">[1] first applied GCN to the recommendation to factorize several rating matrices.</s>
			<s cites="10" anonymised="true">[10] extended it to web-scale recommender systems with neighbor-sampling.</s>
			<s cites="9" anonymised="true">Recently, [9] further approached a more general model that uses high-level connectivity learned by GCN to encode CF signals.</s>
		</context>
	</contexts>
	<references>
		<reference id="1">https://arxiv.org/abs/1706.02263</reference>
		<reference id="2">10.1145/3077136.3080779</reference>
		<reference id="3">https://www.ijcai.org/Proceedings/2019/0290.pdf</reference>
		<reference id="4">10.1145/3397271.3401063</reference>
		<reference id="5">10.1145/3038912.3052569</reference>
		<reference id="6">https://arxiv.org/abs/1609.02907</reference>
		<reference id="7">10.1145/2645710.2645750</reference>
		<reference id="8">10.1145/3077136.3080724</reference>
		<reference id="9">10.5555/1795114.1795167</reference>
		<reference id="10">10.1145/3331184.3331267</reference>
		<reference id="11">10.1145/3219819.3219890</reference>
	</references>
</doc>