<doc>
	<doi>10.1145/3409256.3409847</doi>
	<title>Using Sentiment Analysis for Pseudo-Relevance Feedback in Social Book Search</title>
	<abstract>Book search is a challenging task due to discrepancies between the content and description of books, on one side, and the ways in which people query for books, on the other. However, online reviewers provide an opinionated description of the book, with alternative features that describe the emotional and experiential aspects of the book. Therefore, locating emotional sentences within reviews, could provide a rich alternative source of evidence to help improve book recommendations. Specifically, sentiment analysis (SA) could be employed to identify salient emotional terms, which could then be used for query expansion? This paper explores the employment ofSA based query expansion, in the book search domain. We introduce a sentiment-oriented method for the selection of sentences from the reviews of top rated book. From these sentences, we extract the terms to be employed in the query formulation. The sentence selection process is based on a semi-supervised SA method, which makes use of adapted word embeddings and lexicon seed-words.Using the CLEF 2016 Social Book Search (SBS) Suggestion TrackCollection, an exploratory comparison between standard pseudo-relevance feedback and the proposed sentiment-based approach is performed. The experiments show that the proposed approach obtains 24%-57% improvement over the baselines, whilst the classic technique actually degrades the performance by 14%-51%.</abstract>
	<contexts>
		<context id="01" section="introduction">
			<s>Book search is a difficult Information Retrieval problem due to the vocabulary mismatch between book descriptions and user queries.</s>
			<s cites="13,16">Pseudo-relevance feedback (PRF), also known as blind relevance feedback, is considered as one of the most effective techniques for improving retrieval performance by query reformulation [13, 16].</s>
			<s>As such, PRF provides a way to bridge this semantic gap.</s>
			<s>Typical PRF methods assume the top retrieved documents in the initial retrieval outcome are relevant, and terms are extracted from the pseudo relevant documents based on their term/document statistics.</s>
			<s>These are then employed in the query reformulation process.</s>
			<s cites="8,4,18">However, in the context of book search, where the goal is to rank books given a query [8], the usual application of PRF [4, 18] may not be appropriate, considering that the book’s descriptions may not adequately convey the experience and emotion attached to the story line that a reader may be looking to enjoy.</s>
		</context>
		<context id="02" section="introduction">
			<s>Book social applications (e.g., LibraryThing, Goodreads) offer, in addition to the catalogue of books’ characteristics and/or their partial content, the information generated by users about the books.</s>
			<s>This information is typically constituted by reviews, which include opinions/sentiments and personal descriptions about books that can highlight certain aspects not included in the content of the books’ representations.</s>
			<s>Therefore, once extracted, this information may disclose the experiential and emotional aspects of books that can be used to enrich the query with valuable information.</s>
			<s>However, the extraction of useful information for query expansion from book reviews is problematic.</s>
			<s>The quantity of reviews associated with a book (especially if it is popular) can be very large – and these reviews can be very noisy as they often include content unrelated to book information.</s>
			<s cites="3,17">To alleviate these problems, a number of methods have been proposed, not for query expansion, but to reduce the subset of reviews to be presented to users or for selecting which parts of the reviews to present [3, 17].</s>
			<s cites="17" anonymised="true">For example, [17] used Sentiment Analysis (SA) to highlight sentences with positive or negative sentiment polarity in reviews, to reduce the information overload while reading.</s>
			<s cites="3" anonymised="true">While [3] made use of SA to identify emotionally loaded characters and entities given their proximity to emotional terms (e.g., love, hate) for the purpose of extracting interesting aspects from user comments.</s>
			<s cites="19">Those works, and others before [19], deduced that the SA can be a key factor in the mining and summarization of reviews.</s>
			<s>Given this prior related work, we posit that SA could help by acting as a filter – to limit the set of candidate terms used for expansion – and thus focus on the experiential and emotional aspects of the book.</s>
		</context>
		<context id="03" section="introduction">
			<s>In this paper we present an exploratory study aimed at exploiting SA to identify, in large collections of book reviews, those sentences from which the query expansion terms can be extracted.</s>
			<s>Our intuition is that the writers of book reviews are often guided by the experience and emotions provoked by the book’s content, characters, plot, etc., which they express in a similar way to how readers of the book express their expectations regarding the book.</s>
			<s>For example, given the review: [... my son sat still, absorbing every word. The book has awesome pictures and it delivers a superb message at the end ...], where the user expresses a sentiment for the book’s content with strongly positive expressions, while sharing information about the book.</s>
			<s>The strongly positive sentence in the example is in bold, since it includes strong positive terms underlined.</s>
			<s>The dashed, underlined terms within the strong positive sentence, would be the target to expand the initial query.</s>
			<s>Therefore, we hypothesise that locating sentences within book reviews, which include terms of strong sentiment polarity, may help in identifying useful terms for query expansion.</s>
			<s cites="11,12">On the other hand, using sentiment or emotion in documents to improve the effectiveness of the system has been explored in the past in other domains, such as recommender systems, where [11, 12] used the emotion in reviews to improve the effectiveness of their recommender systems, while in this work we focus on terms’ sentiment intensity rather than general emotion.</s>
			<s cites="7">Also, in the opinion retrieval domain, [7] employed a query expansion method by adding a set of extracted opinion words (e.g., good, like) to the query, extracted from the top retrieved documents in a pseudo relevance feedback method.</s>
			<s cites="7">In their suggestion, [7] served of terms frequency and word weighting techniques, but they did not use any SA methods to classify the documents terms, and they did not go beyond the opinion words extraction to explore the extraction of informative words.</s>
		</context>
	</contexts>
	<references>
		<reference id="1">None</reference>
		<reference id="2">10.1145/383952.384007</reference>
		<reference id="3">10.1145/3209978.3210098</reference>
		<reference id="4">10.1145/1099554.1099725</reference>
		<reference id="5">https://www.aclweb.org/anthology/P07-1056.pdf</reference>
		<reference id="6">https://ci.nii.ac.jp/naid/10020493560/</reference>
		<reference id="7">10.1145/1645953.1646075</reference>
		<reference id="8">10.1007/978-3-319-44564-9_29</reference>
		<reference id="9">10.1145/2766462.2767755</reference>
		<reference id="10">https://arxiv.org/abs/1301.3781</reference>
		<reference id="11">10.1145/2009916.2010001</reference>
		<reference id="12">10.1145/3320435.3320457</reference>
		<reference id="13">https://ci.nii.ac.jp/naid/10000074359/</reference>
		<reference id="14">10.1145/944012.944013</reference>
		<reference id="15">http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.30.1166&amp;rep=rep1&amp;type=pdf</reference>
		<reference id="16">10.1145/243199.243202</reference>
		<reference id="17">10.1108/OIR-04-2017-0114</reference>
		<reference id="18">10.1145/2600428.2609636</reference>
		<reference id="19">10.1145/1183614.1183625</reference>
	</references>
</doc>